<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
  <comment>
    * $Id$
    * $URL$
    * ---------------------------------------------------------------------
    * This file is part of SBMLsqueezer, a Java program that creates rate 
    * equations for reactions in SBML files (http://sbml.org).
    *
    * Copyright (C) 2006-2015 by the University of Tuebingen, Germany.
    *
    * This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    * it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
    * the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
    * (at your option) any later version.
    *
    * This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    * but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    * MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the
    * GNU General Public License for more details.
    *
    * You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
    * along with this program. If not, see http://www.gnu.org/licenses/.
    * ---------------------------------------------------------------------
    * 
    * Version: $Rev$
 
	This configuration provides locale-dependent names for warnings and error
	messages in a (graphical) user interface.
	Although the preferred way would be to have separate key-value pairs for
	actual labels and their corresponding tooltips, you may want to use just 
	one key-value pair, in which the tooltip is located after the separator 
	";". Otherwise, please use the suffix "_TOOLTIP" to indicate a tooltip 
	for some label.
	
	Please see the JavaDoc for MessageFormatter and Formatter. 
  </comment>
  
  <entry key="BUILDING_DATA_STRUCTURES">Building data structures...</entry>
  <entry key="CANNOT_INITIALIZE_SBMLSQUEEZER">Unable to initialize SBMLsqueezer</entry>
  <entry key="CONFIGURE">Preferences</entry>
  <entry key="CONFIGURE_TOOLTIP">Define your preferences for the behavior of SBMLsqueezer</entry>
  <entry key="DEFAULT_OPTION">invalid option</entry>
  <entry key="EXPORT_ALL">Create model report</entry>
  <entry key="EXPORT_ALL_TOOLTIP">Launch SBML2LaTeX to write a comprehensive model report that gives a better overview about the content of the current model. If you have LaTeX installed on your system, you can directly generate a PDF file, which SBML2LaTeXr will display upon creation. You can also store just the TeX file, which can help you preparing your paper.</entry>
  <entry key="EXPORT_REACTION">Export reaction to other format</entry>
  <entry key="EXPORT_REACTION_TOOLTIP">Launch SBML2LaTeX to create a report file describing the current reaction with all of its participants and components and store it in a file. If you have LaTeX installed on your system, SBML2LaTeX can directly display the resulting PDF file upon creation. You can also generate a TeX file to support scientific writing.</entry>
  <entry key="INTERNAL_DATA_STRUCTURE">Internal JSBML data structure</entry>
  <entry key="NO_SELECTED_MODEL_AVAILABLE">No selected model available</entry>
  <entry key="ONLINE_HELP">Help</entry>
  <entry key="ONLINE_HELP_TOOLTIP">Display the online help including basic information about SBMLsqueezer, command-line usage and further information.</entry>
  <entry key="SQUEEZE_ALL">Squeeze kinetic laws</entry>
  <entry key="SQUEEZE_ALL_TOOLTIP">Open the kinetic law wizard and create equations for all reactions within the model in a single go.</entry>
  <entry key="SQUEEZE_REACTION">Squeeze kinetic law</entry>
  <entry key="SQUEEZE_REACTION_TOOLTIP">Generate a kinetic law for the currently selected reaction.</entry>
  <entry key="SHOW_JSBML_MODEL">Show the data structure</entry>
  <entry key="SHOW_JSBML_MODEL_TOOLTIP">Display the content of the current model in an alternative way, including all model components.</entry>
  <entry key="UNSUPPORTED_ACTION">Unsupported action {0}</entry>
  <entry key="UNSUPPORTED_SOURCE_OF_ACTION">Unsupported source of action {0}</entry>
  
  <!-- Log messages -->
  <entry key="CONVERTING_DATA_STRUCTURE">Converting CellDesigner's data structure to JSBML objects</entry>
  <entry key="SQUEEZING_ALL">Squeeze all kinetic equations</entry>
  <entry key="SQUEEZING_REACTION">Squeeze reaction {0}.</entry>
  <entry key="CONFIGURATION">Configuration</entry>
  <entry key="SBML2LATEX_FOR_REACTION">Launching LaTeX export for Reaction {0}.</entry>
  <entry key="SBML2LATEX_FOR_DOCUMENT">Launching LaTeX export for SBMLDocument</entry>
  
</properties>
