<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
  <comment>
	This configuration describes the labels of options in SBMLsqueezer-related 
	(graphical) user interfaces.
	Although the preferred way would be to have separate key-value pairs for
	actual labels and their corresponding tooltips, you may want to use just 
	one key-value pair, in which the tooltip is located after the separator 
	";". Otherwise, please use the suffix "_TOOLTIP" to indicate a tooltip 
	for some label.
	
	Please see the JavaDoc for MessageFormatter and Formatter. 
  </comment>
  
  <!-- SqueezerOptions -->
  <entry key="SqueezerOptions">SBMLsqueezer Options</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_ARBITRARY_ENZYME_REACTIONS">Kinetics aribitary enzyme reactions</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_ARBITRARY_ENZYME_REACTIONS_TOOLTIP">Determines the key for the standard kinetic law to be applied for reactions that are identified to be enzyme-catalyzed (with or without explicit catalyst) and that do not belong to one of the other standard enzyme-catalysis schemes. The value can be any rate law that implements InterfaceArbitraryEnzymeKinetics.</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_ARBITRARY_ENZYME_REACTIONS_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Reactions, which are enzyme-catalyzed, and follow none of the schemes uni-uni, bi-uni and bi-bi can be modeled using {0}.</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_BI_BI_TYPE">Kinetics bi-bi type</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_BI_BI_TYPE_TOOLTIP">The class name of the default kinetic law for bi-bi reactions. This can be any class that implements InterfaceBiBiKinetics</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_BI_BI_TYPE_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Check this box if you want the {0} to be applied to all bi-bi reactions (two reactants, two products).</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_BI_UNI_TYPE">Kinetics bi-uni type</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_BI_UNI_TYPE_TOOLTIP">The class name of the default kinetic law for bi-uni reactions. This can be any class that implements InterfaceBiUniKinetics</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_BI_UNI_TYPE_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Check this box if you want the {0} scheme as reaction scheme for bi-uni reactions (two reactant, one product).</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_GENE_REGULATION">Kinetics gene regulation</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_GENE_REGULATION_TOOLTIP">Determines the key for the standard kinetic law to be applied for reactions that are identified to belong to gene-regulatory processes,such as transcription or translation. The value is the class name of any class that implements InterfaceGeneRegulatoryNetworks</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_GENE_REGULATION_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Check this box if you want {0} as reaction scheme for gene regulation (reactions involving genes, RNA and proteins)</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_NONE_ENZYME_REACTIONS">Kinetics none enzyme reactions</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_NONE_ENZYME_REACTIONS_TOOLTIP">Determines the key for the standard kinetic law to be applied for reactions that are catalyzed by non-enzymes or that are not catalyzed at all. The value may be any rate law that implements InterfaceNonEnzymeKinetics</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_UNI_UNI_TYPE">Kinetics uni-uni type</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_UNI_UNI_TYPE_TOOLTIP">This key defines the default kinetic law to be applied to enzyme-catalyzed reactions with one reactant and one product. Possible values are the names of classes that implement InterfaceUniUniKinetics.</entry>
  <entry key="KINETICS_UNI_UNI_TYPE_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Check this box if {0} is to be applied for uni-uni reactions (one reactant, one product).</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_ADD_NEW_PARAMETERS_ALWAYS_GLOBALLY">Add all new parameters globally</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_ADD_NEW_PARAMETERS_ALWAYS_GLOBALLY_TOOLTIP">"If true (default), all parameters are stored globally for the whole model. Otherwise parameters are stored locally for the respective kinetic equation they belong to.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_ADD_NEW_PARAMETERS_ALWAYS_GLOBALLY_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If selected, all newly created parameters are stored globally in the model. Otherwise SBMLsqueezer only stores most parameters locally in the respective rate law.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_ALL_REACTIONS_ARE_ENZYME_CATALYZED">Consider all reactions to be enzyme-catalyzed</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_ALL_REACTIONS_ARE_ENZYME_CATALYZED_TOOLTIP">If true, all reactions within the network are considered enzyme reactions. If false (default), an explicit enzymatic catalyst must be assigned to a reaction to obtain this status.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_ALL_REACTIONS_ARE_ENZYME_CATALYZED_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, all reactions are considered to be enzyme-catalyzed.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_COMPARTMENT_INITIAL_SIZE">Default compartment initial size</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_COMPARTMENT_INITIAL_SIZE_TOOLTIP">For compartments that are not yet initialized, SBMLsqueezer will use this value as the default initial size. By default this value is set to 1.0d.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_COMPARTMENT_INITIAL_SIZE_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">For compartments that are not yet initialized, SBMLsqueezer will use this value as the default initial size.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_SPECIES_INITIAL_VALUE">Default species initial value</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_SPECIES_INITIAL_VALUE_TOOLTIP">"If species are not yet initialized, SBMLsqueezer will use this value as initial amount or initial concentration of the species depending on their hasOnlySubstanceUnits property, i.e., for species that are interpreted in terms of concentration, an initial concentration will be set, whereas an initial amount will be set if the species is to be interpreted in terms of molecule counts. By default this value is set to 1.0d.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_SPECIES_INITIAL_VALUE_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If species are not yet initialized, SBMLsqueezer will use this value as initial amount or initial concentration of the species depending on its hasOnlySubstanceUnits value, i.e., for species that are interpreted in terms of concentration, an initial concentration will be set, whereas an initial amount will be set if the species is to be interpreted in terms of molecule counts.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_VALUE_OF_NEW_PARAMETERS">Default value of new parameters</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_VALUE_OF_NEW_PARAMETERS_TOOLTIP">The default value that is set for newly created parameters. By default this value is 1.0d.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_DEFAULT_VALUE_OF_NEW_PARAMETERS_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Specifiy the default value for newly created parameters.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_GENERATE_KINETIC_LAW_FOR_EACH_REACTION">For all reactions</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_GENERATE_KINETIC_LAW_FOR_EACH_REACTION_TOOLTIP">If true, a new rate law will be created for each reaction irrespective of whether there is already a rate law assigned to this reaction or not. If false (default), new rate laws are only generated if missing in the SBML file.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_GENERATE_KINETIC_LAW_FOR_EACH_REACTION_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, already existing kinetic laws will be overwritten.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_GENERATE_KINETIC_LAW_ONLY_WHEN_MISSING">Only when missing</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_GENERATE_KINETIC_LAW_ONLY_WHEN_MISSING_TOOLTIP">If checked, kinetics are only generated if missing in the SBML file.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_IGNORE_THESE_SPECIES_WHEN_CREATING_LAWS">Ignore these species when creating laws</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_IGNORE_THESE_SPECIES_WHEN_CREATING_LAWS_TOOLTIP">Allows the user to ignore species that are annotated with the given compound identifiers when creating rate laws for reactions that involve these species. For instance, water or single protons can often be ignored when creating rate equations, hence simplifying the resulting rate equations. Preselected are the KEGG compound identifiers for water and protons.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_MAX_NUMBER_OF_REACTANTS">Maximum number of reactants</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_MAX_NUMBER_OF_REACTANTS_TOOLTIP">The maximal number of reactants so that the reaction is still considered plausible. By default this value is set to 3.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_MAX_NUMBER_OF_REACTANTS_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Specifiy how many reactants are at most likely to collide. This option is only available if warnings should be displayed at all.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_REMOVE_UNNECESSARY_PARAMETERS_AND_UNITS">Remove uneccessary parameters and units</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_REMOVE_UNNECESSARY_PARAMETERS_AND_UNITS_TOOLTIP">If true (default), parameters and units that are never referenced by any element of the model are deleted when creating kinetic equations with SBMLsqueezer.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_REMOVE_UNNECESSARY_PARAMETERS_AND_UNITS_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If selected parameters and unit definitions that are never referenced in the model are automatically deleted when creating new kinetic laws.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_SET_BOUNDARY_CONDITION_FOR_GENES">Set boundary condition for gene coding species</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_SET_BOUNDARY_CONDITION_FOR_GENES_TOOLTIP">If true (default), the boundary condition of all species that represent gene coding elements, such as genes or gene coding regions will be set to true.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_SET_BOUNDARY_CONDITION_FOR_GENES_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If selected, the boundary condition of all species that represent gene coding elements, such as genes or gene coding regions will be set to true.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_TREAT_ALL_REACTIONS_REVERSIBLE">Model all reactions in a reversible manner</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_TREAT_ALL_REACTIONS_REVERSIBLE_TOOLTIP">If true (default), all reactions are set to reversible before creating new kinetic equations. Otherwise the information given by the SBML file will be left unchanged.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_TREAT_ALL_REACTIONS_REVERSIBLE_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, all reactions will be set to reversible no matter what is given by the SBML file.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_TREAT_ALL_REACTIONS_REVERSIBLE_AS_CD">Use information from SBML</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_TREAT_ALL_REACTIONS_REVERSIBLE_AS_CD_TOOLTIP">If checked, the information about reversiblity will be left unchanged.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_WARNINGS_FOR_TOO_MANY_REACTANTS">Warnings for too many reactants:</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_WARNINGS_FOR_TOO_MANY_REACTANTS_TOOLTIP">If true (default), warnings will be displayed for reactions with more reactants than specified by the opt-max-number-of-reactants option.</entry>
  <entry key="OPT_WARNINGS_FOR_TOO_MANY_REACTANTS_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, warnings will be shown for reactions with more reactants than specified here.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_ANTISENSE_RNA">asRNA</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_ANTISENSE_RNA_TOOLTIP">If true, antisense RNA molecules are treated as enzymes when catalyzing a reaction. If false (default) antisense RNA molecule catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme-catalyzed reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_ANTISENSE_RNA_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, asRNA is treated as an enzyme. Otherwise asRNA catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme-catalyzed reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_COMPLEX">Complex</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_COMPLEX_TOOLTIP">If true (default), complex molecules are treated as enzymes when catalyzing a reaction. Otherwise, complex catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_COMPLEX_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, complex molecules are treated as enzymes. Otherwise, complex catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_GENERIC">Generic protein</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_GENERIC_TOOLTIP">If true (default), generic proteins are treated as enzymes when catalyzing a reaction. Otherwise, generic protein-catalyzed reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_GENERIC_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, generic proteins are treated as enzymes. Otherwise, generic protein-catalyzed reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_MACROMOLECULE">Macromolecule</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_MACROMOLECULE_TOOLTIP">If this options is selected, species that are annotated as macromolecules are treated as enzymes when catalyzing a reaction. Otherwise, macormolecule-catalyzed reactions are not considered enzyme reactions. If a modifier of a reaction that is annotated as an enzymatic catalyst refers to a macromolecule but this option is not active, SBMLsqueezer will reduce the modifier to a simple catalyst.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_RECEPTOR">Receptor</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_RECEPTOR_TOOLTIP">If true, receptors are treated as enzymes. when catalyzing a reaction. If false (default), receptor catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_RECEPTOR_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, receptors are treated as enzymes. Otherwise, receptor catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_RNA">RNA</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_RNA_TOOLTIP">If true (default), RNA is treated as an enzyme when catalyzing a reaction. Otherwise RNA catalyzed reactions are not considered to be enzyme-catalyzed reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_RNA_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, RNA is treated as an enzyme. Otherwise RNA catalyzed reactions are not considered to be enzyme-catalyzed reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_SIMPLE_MOLECULE">Simple molecule</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_SIMPLE_MOLECULE_TOOLTIP">If true, simple molecules are treated as enzymes when catalyzing a reaction. If false (default), simple molecule catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_SIMPLE_MOLECULE_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, simple molecules are treated as enzymes. Otherwise, simple molecule catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_TRUNCATED">Truncated protein</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_TRUNCATED_TOOLTIP">If true (default), truncated proteins are treated as enzymes when catalyzing a reaction. Otherwise, truncated protein catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_TRUNCATED_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, truncated proteins are treated as enzymes. Otherwise, truncated protein catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_UNKNOWN">Unknown</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_UNKNOWN_TOOLTIP">If true, unknown molecules are treated as enzymes when catalyzing a reaction. If false (default), unknown molecule catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="POSSIBLE_ENZYME_UNKNOWN_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If checked, unknown molecules are treated as enzymes. Otherwise, unknown molecule catalized reactions are not considered to be enzyme reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="SBML_IN_FILE">SBML input file</entry>
  <entry key="SBML_IN_FILE_TOOLTIP">Specifies the SBML input file.</entry>
  <entry key="SBML_OUT_FILE">SBML output file</entry>
  <entry key="SBML_OUT_FILE_TOOLTIP">Specifies the file where SBMLsqueezer writes its SBML output.</entry>
  <entry key="SHOW_SBML_WARNINGS">Show SBML warnings</entry>
  <entry key="SHOW_SBML_WARNINGS_TOOLTIP">If true (default), SBML warnings are displayed.</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_STANDARD_VERSION">Version of modular rate laws</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_STANDARD_VERSION_TOOLTIP">This option declares the version of the modular rate laws and can attain the three different values cat, hal and weg as described in the publications of Liebermeister et al. 2010. This option can only be accessed if all reactions are modeled reversibly.</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_STANDARD_VERSION_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">Select the version of the modular rate laws. These options are described in the publications of Liebermeister et al. 2010. This option can only be accessed if all reactions are modeled reversibly.</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_UNIT_CONSISTENCY">Bring species to substance units</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_UNIT_CONSISTENCY_TOOLTIP">This option ensures unit consistency and can attain two different values: Choose amount to set each participating species to an initial amount with the unit mmole. If the hasOnlySubstanceUnits option is set to false the species will then be multiplied with the size of the surrounding compartment whenever it occurs in a kinetic equation. Choose concentration to set each participating species to an initial concentration with the unit mmole per l. In this case the species will be divided by the surrounding compartment size when it occurs in a kinetic equation, and if its hasOnlySubstanceUnits attribute is set to false. The units of parameters are set accordingly.</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_UNIT_CONSISTENCY_TOOLTIP_TO_BE_MERGED">If this option is selected, species occuring in kinetic equations are multiplyed with the size of the surrounding compartment if their hasOnlySubstanceUnits attribute is set to false. The units of parameters are set accordingly.</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_UNITS_COMPARTMENT">Bring species to concentration units</entry>
  <entry key="TYPE_UNITS_COMPARTMENT_TOOLTIP">If this option is selected, species are interpreted in terms of concentration and are therefore divided by their surrounding compartment size when these occur in kinetic equations and their hasOnlySubstanceUnits attribute is false. The units of parameters are set accordingly.</entry>
  
  <!-- StabilityOptions -->
  <entry key="STEUER_VALUE_OF_N"></entry>
  <entry key="STEUER_VALUE_OF_N_TOOLTIP">Explanation...</entry>
  
</properties>