<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE properties SYSTEM "http://java.sun.com/dtd/properties.dtd">
<properties>
  <comment>
	This configuration provides locale-dependent names for warnings and error
	messages in a (graphical) user interface.
	Although the preferred way would be to have separate key-value pairs for
	actual labels and their corresponding tooltips, you may want to use just 
	one key-value pair, in which the tooltip is located after the separator 
	";". Otherwise, please use the suffix "_TOOLTIP" to indicate a tooltip 
	for some label.
	
	Please see the JavaDoc for MessageFormatter and Formatter. 
  </comment>
  
  <entry key="WARNING">Warning</entry>
  <entry key="SBML_WARNINGS">SBML warnings</entry>
  
  <!-- KineticLawSelectionPanel -->
  <entry key="INVALID_RATE_LAW_COUNT">at least one rate law must be given and the index must be between zero and the number of rate laws.</entry>

  <!-- KineticLawGenerator -->
  <entry key="INVALID_COMPARTMENT_DIMENSION">Compartment {0} had an invalid spacial dimension and was therefore set to a volume.</entry>
  <entry key="INVALID_REACTION_FORMAT">Reaction {0} in the model has an incorrect format. This means there is either an empty kinetic law in this reaction or a kinetic law that only consists of a white space. If you decide not to save this generated model, there is only one solution: open this SBML file in an editor and delete the whole kinetic law. SBMLsqueezer ignores this misstake and generates a proper equation. Therfore we recomment that you save this generated model.</entry>
  <entry key="INVALID_REACTION_ID_FOR_RATE_LAW_CREATION">{0} is not the id of a reaction for which rate laws are to be created.</entry>
  
  <!-- ParameterFactory -->
  <entry key="UNDEFINED_COMPARTMENT_OF_SPECIES">The compartment of species "{0}" is undefined.</entry>
  <entry key="UNDEFINED_UNIT_OF_SPECIES">Could not assign units to parameter "{0}" due to undefined units of species "{1}".</entry>
  
  <!-- ReactionType -->
  <entry key="REACTION_MUST_BE_TRANSRIPTION">Reaction {0} must be a transcription.</entry>
  <entry key="REACTION_MUST_BE_TRANSLATION">Reaction {0} must be a tranlation.</entry>
  <entry key="REACTION_MUST_BE_TRANSITION">Reaction {0} must be a transition.</entry>
  
  <!-- SBMLsqueezer -->
  <entry key="CANT_READ_MODEL">A problem occured while trying to read the model {0}</entry>
  <entry key="SQUEEZE_ERROR">input: {0}, output: {1}</entry>
  <entry key="OUTPUT_ERROR">Could not write output to SBML.</entry>
  <entry key="FILE_CONTAINS_NO_MODEL">File contains no model. Nothing to do.</entry>
  <entry key="INVALID_TEX_FILE">no valid TeX file: {0}</entry>
  <entry key="NO_TEX_FILE_PROVIDED">no TeX file was provided</entry>
  
  <!-- SBMLsqueezerUI -->
  <entry key="UNABLE_TO_LOAD_MODEL">Unable to load this model due to one or several errors. Please use the SBML online validator to check why this model is not correct.</entry>
  
  <!-- SqSBMLReader -->
  <entry key="WRONG_MODEL_INSTANCE">model must be an instance of java.lang.String, org.sbml.jsbml.Model or org.sbml.jsbml.SBMLDocument</entry>
  
  <!-- SqSBMLWriter -->
  <entry key="NO_JSBML_MODEL">only instances of org.sbml.jsbml.Model can be considered.</entry>
  <entry key="NO_JSBML_MODEL_OR_SBMLDOCUMENT">object must be an instance of org.sbml.jsbml.SBMLDocument or org.sbml.jsbml.Model.</entry>
  
  <!-- IrrevCompetNonCooperativeEnzymes -->
  <entry key="RATE_LAW_CAN_ONLY_APPLIED_TO_ENZYME_CATALYZED_REACTIONS">This rate law can only be applied to enzyme-catalyzed reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="RATE_LAW_CAN_ONLY_APPLIED_TO_REACTIONS_WITH_EXACTLY_ONE_SUBSTRATE_SPECIES">This rate law can only be applied to reactions with exactly one substrate species.</entry>
  
  <!-- IrrevNonModulatedNonInteractingEnzymes -->
  <entry key="RATE_LAW_CAN_ONLY_APPLIED_TO_NON_MODULATED_REACTIONS">This rate law can only be applied to non-modulated reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="RATE_LAW_CAN_ONLY_APPLIED_TO_IRREVERSIBLE_REACTIONS">This rate law can only be applied to irreversible reactions.</entry>
  <entry key="RATE_LAW_CAN_ONLY_APPLIED_IF_REACTANTS_HAVE_INTEGER_STOICHIOMETRIES">This rate law can only be applied if all reactants have integer stoichiometries.</entry>
  
  <!-- MichaelisMenten -->
  <entry key="INCORRECT_STOICHIOMETRY_OF_REACTANT_SPECIES">{0} cannot be applied to reaction {1} because the stoichiometry of the reactant species does not sum up to 1.0.</entry>
  <entry key="INCORRECT_STOICHIOMETRY_OF_PRODUCT_SPECIES">Reversible {0} cannot be applied to reaction {1} because the stoichiometry of the product species does not sum up to 1.0.</entry>
  
  <!-- OrderedMechanism -->
  <entry key="ORDERED_NUM_OF_REACTANTS_MUST_EQUAL">Number of reactants must equal two to apply ordered Michaelis-Menten kinetics to reaction {0}.</entry>
  <entry key="ORDERED_NUM_OF_PRODUCTS_MUST_EQUAL">For reversible reactions the number of products must equal either one or two to apply ordered kinetics to reaction {0}.</entry>
  
  <!-- PingPongMechanism -->
  <entry key="PING_PONG_NUM_OF_REACTANTS_MUST_EQUAL">Number of reactants must equal two to apply ping-pong Michaelis-Menten kinetics to reaction {0}.</entry>
  <entry key="PING_PONG_NUM_OF_PRODUCTS_MUST_EQUAL">Number of products must equal two to apply ping-pong Michaelis-Menten kinetics to reaction {0}.</entry>
  
  <!-- RandomOrderMechanism -->
  <entry key="RANDOM_ORDER_NUM_OF_REACTANTS_MUST_EQUAL">Number of reactants must equal two to apply random order Michaelis-Menten kinetics to reaction {0}.</entry>
  <entry key="RANDOM_ORDER_NUM_OF_PRODUCTS_MUST_EQUAL">For reversible reactions the number of products must equal either one or two to apply random order Michaelis-Menten kinetics to reaction {0}.</entry>
  
  <!-- SBMLtools -->
  <entry key="COULD_NOT_SET_SBO_TERM">Could not set SBO term {0} for {1} with Level = {2} and Version = {3}.</entry>

</properties>